In the previous video, we talked about Stochastic gradient descent, and how that can be much faster than Batch gradient descent.
在前面的视频中，我们讨论了随机梯度下降算法，并讨论了它如何比批量梯度下降算法快。（字幕翻译：中国海洋大学，仇利克）
In this video, let's talk about another variation on these ideas is called Mini-batch gradient descent
这个视频，我们讨论这种思想的另外一种变种，称为微型批量梯度下降，
they can work sometimes even a bit faster than stochastic gradient descent.
它们有时甚至比随机梯度下降还要快一点。
To summarize the algorithms we talked about so far.
总而言之，我们迄今为止讲过的算法。
In Batch gradient descent we will use all m examples in each generation.
批量梯度下降算法中，每次迭代，我们都要用到所有的m个样本。
Whereas in Stochastic gradient descent we will use a single example in each generation.
而在随机梯度下降算法中，每次迭代只需使用一个样本。
What Mini-batch gradient descent does is somewhere in between.
微型批量梯度下降算法介于两者之间。
Specifically, with this algorithm we're going to use b examples in each iteration where b is a parameter called the "mini batch size"
特别的，微型批量梯度下降算法中，每次迭代我们将使用b个样本，b是一个称为“小批量大小”的参数。
so the idea is that this is somewhat in-between Batch gradient descent and Stochastic gradient descent.
所以，它是介于批量梯度下降算法和随机梯度下降算法中间的一种算法。
This is just like batch gradient descent, except that I'm going to use a much smaller batch size.
这正如批量梯度下降算法，只是我们将用一个少得多的批量大小。
A typical choice for the value of b might be b equals 10, lets say, and a typical range really might be anywhere from b equals 2 up to b equals 100.
通常选择b等于10，b通常的变化范围是2到100.
So that will be a pretty typical range of values for the Mini-batch size.
对微型批量梯度下降算法，这将是一个常用的取值范围。
And the idea is that rather than using one example at a time or m examples at a time we will use b examples at a time.
它的思想是，既不是一次使用一个样本，也不是一次使用m个样本，而是一次使用b个样本。
So let me just write this out informally, we're going to get, let's say, b. For this example, let's say b equals 10.
因此让我将它非正式的写下来，我们将得到b，比如，让b等于10.
So we're going to get, the next 10 examples from my training set so that may be some set of examples xi, yi.
因此我们将从训练集中得到后续的10个样本，可能是xi, yi的一些组合。
If it's 10 examples then the indexing will be up to x (i+9), y (i+9)
如果是10个样本，下标最大是x(i+9), y(i+9)，
so that's 10 examples altogether and then we'll perform essentially a gradient descent update using these 10 examples.
我们将使用这10个样本执行梯度下降算法，完成更新。
So, that's any rate times one tenth times sum over k equals i through i+9 of h subscript theta of x(k) minus y(k) times x(k)j.
因此，k=i:i+9,theta等于theta减去一个10次求和，这个求和公式等于（hx(k)-y(k)）*x(k)j.
And so in this expression, where summing the gradient terms over my ten examples.
在以上表述中，是在10个样本上进行梯度求和。
So, that's number ten, that's, you know, my mini batch size and just i+9 again,
因此，那是数字10，你知道的，我最小的批量大小，仅仅i+9，
the 9 comes from the choice of the parameter b, and then after this we will then increase, you know,
9来自我们对参数b的选择，运算完后，我们将增加i到10，你知道的
i by tenth, we will go on to the next ten examples and then keep moving like this.
我们将继续使用后续的10个样本，并像这样一直进行下去。
So just to write out the entire algorithm in full.
因此，让我写下完整的算法。
In order to simplify the indexing for this one at the right top,
为了简化下标
I'm going to assume we have a mini-batch size of ten and a training set size of a thousand,
假设我有最小批量大小为10，训练样本大小为1000，
what we're going to do is have this sort of form, for i equals 1 and that in 21's the stepping,
我们要做的是使用这种形式，i=1，在第21步，
in steps of 10 because we look at 10 examples at a time.
步骤10，因为我们每次使用10个样本。
And then we perform this sort of gradient descent update using ten examples at a time
然后，我们执行梯度下降算法，一次用10个样本进行更新，
so this 10 and this i+9 those are consequence of having chosen my mini-batch to be ten.
10和i+9都说明我的微型批量梯度下降算法选择的是10个样本。
And you know, this ultimate four-loop, this ends at 991 here because
你知道的，这个终极for循环，它在991结束，因为
if I have 1000 training samples then I need 100 steps of size 10 in order to get through my training set.
如果我有1000个训练样本，我需要循环100次，每次10步才能遍历我的整个训练集。
So this is mini-batch gradient descent.
这就是微型批量梯度下降算法。
Compared to batch gradient descent, this also allows us to make progress much faster.
与批量梯度下降相比，微型批量梯度下降速度更快。
So we have again our running example of, you know, U.S. Census data with 300 million training examples,
因此，我们有了运行实例，你知道的，3亿条美国人口普查数据的训练样本，
then what we're saying is after looking at just the first 10 examples we can start to make progress
然后我们想说的是，仅仅遍历前面10个样本后，我们就可以运行算法
in improving the parameters theta so we don't need to scan through the entire training set.
更新参数theta，因此，我们不需要遍历整个训练样本集。
We just need to look at the first 10 examples and this will start letting us make progress and then
我们仅仅需要前面10个样本就可以运行算法，然后
we can look at the second ten examples and modify the parameters a little bit again and so on.
我们通过使用后续的10个样本来更新参数theta，以此类推。
So, that is why Mini-batch gradient descent can be faster than batch gradient descent.
因此，这就是为什么微型批量梯度下降算法比批量梯度下降算法要快。
Namely, you can start making progress in modifying the parameters after looking at just ten examples
也就是说，我们仅仅使用前面的10个样本就可以运行算法更新参数，
rather than needing to wait 'till you've scan through every single training example of 300 million of them.
而不需要等我们遍历完所有的3亿个样本后才能执行算法更新参数。
So, how about Mini-batch gradient descent versus Stochastic gradient descent.
因此，微型批量梯度下降算法与随机梯度下降算法比如何呢。
So, why do we want to look at b examples at a time rather than look at just a single example at a time as the Stochastic gradient descent?
为什么我们每次使用b个样本而不是像随机梯度下降算法每次使用一个样本？
The answer is in vectorization.
答案是在向量化。
In particular, Mini-batch gradient descent is likely to outperform Stochastic gradient descent
特别的，微型批量梯度下降算法胜过随机梯度下降算法
only if you have a good vectorized implementation.
仅当你有一个好的向量化实施。
In that case, the sum over 10 examples can be performed in a more vectorized way
那样的话，10个样本的总和可以以更向量化的方式执行，
which will allow you to partially parallelize your computation over the ten examples.
这将允许你在10个样本上部分的实现并行计算。
So, in other words, by using appropriate vectorization to compute the rest of the terms,
因此，换句话说，通过使用适当的向量化计算余下的样本，
you can sometimes partially use the good numerical algebra libraries and parallelize your gradient computations over the b examples,
有时你可以部分的使用好数值代数库，在b个样本上并行你的梯度计算，
whereas if you were looking at just a single example of time with Stochastic gradient descent then, you know,
然而，如果你像随机梯度下降算法一样每次仅遍历一个样本，你知道的，
just looking at one example at a time their isn't much to parallelize over.
一次仅遍历一个样本并没有太多的并行计算。
At least there is less to parallelize over.
至少，有很少的并行计算。
One disadvantage of Mini-batch gradient descent is that there is now this extra parameter b,
微型批量梯度下降算法的缺点是，有一个额外的参数b，
the Mini-batch size which you may have to fiddle with, and which may therefore take time.
你需要确定b的大小，因此可能需要费些时间。
But if you have a good vectorized implementation this can sometimes run even faster than Stochastic gradient descent.
但是，如果你有一个很好地量化实现，有时它将比随机梯度下降运行的更快。
So that was Mini-batch gradient descent which is an algorithm that in some sense does something
这就是微型批量梯度下降算法，某种意义上来说，它是一种介于
that's somewhat in between what Stochastic gradient descent does and what Batch gradient descent does.
随机梯度下降和批量梯度下降算法中间的一种算法。
And if you choose their reasonable value of b. I usually use b equals 10, but,
如果你选择了合适的参数b。我通常使b等于10，但是
you know, other values, anywhere from say 2 to 100, would be reasonably common.
你知道的，另外一些值，从2到100，都将是合理的范围。
So we choose value of b and if you use a good vectorized implementation,
因此我们选择b的值，如果使用一个好的量化实现，
sometimes it can be faster than both Stochastic gradient descent and faster than Batch gradient descent.
有时候它会比随机梯度下降算法和批量梯度下降算法的速度都要快。